A daughter lost.
A son found.
He is yours.
Evadne Barwell?
since you have
proven your commitment
Boston is now officially open for
the importation of your merchandise.
Jack says just a few more
weeks and you will be free
Stories about you
come up the canal.
Once you walked fine alone,
now you need a stick.
You stay clean for two weeks,
I'll write Linda another letter.
Have you recently
suffered seizures?
It is Tuberculoma, I am
afraid it is inoperable.
Mr Shelby.
I only gave opium
to your brother
because he give me big trouble.
He attacked my wife.
I would like a pot
of green tea, please.
It has taken me ten years
to build this business.
Your business will be
safe, if you do what I say.
How much opium do you
have in your cellar?
Five pounds.
Bring it to me.
Four minutes against the clock.
As member of Parliament,
for this constituency
it is my duty to take
responsibility for the welfare
of my constituents. Mr Shelby,
the clock is still ticking.
The consumption of opium is
very prejudicial to health.
Women give it to their
children so they can leave
them untended while they
work in the factories.
Men lose their jobs when
they become addicted.
From now on, you will sell
only cigarettes, cake and tea.
If I hear that you are
selling opium again,
time will indeed run out very
quickly for you. Do you understand?
Yes, I understand, I will stop.
Mr Shelby, the clock
is still ticking.
I dodn't think it's a real bomb
Please tell
your suppliers
and your customers
that from now on
there will be no more opium
in Small Heath or in Bordesley.
Thank you for the tea.
You see.
It was not a real bomb
You can let them through now.
Yes, sir, Mr Shelby.
You tell the pub and cafe
owners in Montague Street
if there is any further
trade in powder,
there will be no
more Montague Street.
I will have it demolished
and replaced by apartments.
By order of Birmingham
Urban District Council.
Sorry I'm late, they
closed Montague Street.
There's a gas explosion or...
Right. Well, it would be
nice if just one thing
could happen in Birmingham
that wasn't our fault.
I have gathered you all here
today because there is news
and it is of interest
to the whole family.
First of all,
I would like to
welcome Finn's new wife
Mary to the family.
Right. Well, I'm very glad I
dragged myself out of bed for this.
There is
one more item of business.
Johnny.
Tom.
Come on, come on, hurry up.
Everyone
this here is Erasmus.
Nobody calls me that.
They call him Duke.
20 years ago, at
Appleby horse fair...
I met a girl.
We shared the shade
of a hazel tree.
Nine months later
this lad was born.
This is my son.
His mother died on the road.
Up until now I never
tried to find him.
But I am trying to look at
life in a different way.
A child is a precious thing.
So I am bringing him...
Into the fucking family
with a snap of his fingers.
No, I am bringing
him into the fold.
He'll have to earn
membership of the family.
For the moment, welcome,
son. You have a seat.
Go on, sit down here.
There are some
mistakes I've made
that I can never address,
and some I can.
Some wounds I can try to heal.
And new wounds you can open up.
Anyway
that's the business of the day.
Is it too early for whisky?
There you go.
Shelby breakfast for you, son.
I don't drink.
And I'm not a Shelby,
all right?I'm a Duke.
Ooh, hoo, hoo, hoo.
You're a fucking
Shelby, all right,
don't worry about that.
Mm, I think we will need Curly
and a strong rope to
break this one in, Tom.
Arthur, open up the shop,
put the kid here on the
blackboard, writing up the odds.
I can't write.
Put the kid on the blackboard,
wiping off the chalk.
Go on, son.
Come on then.
Lizzie,
come on.
My father was the Duke
of the Saxon Shore.
My mother was a Romany Queen.
Who told you that, your mum?
I don't allow people to
talk about my mother.
Good for you.
So let's get this right
then, you can't read,
you can't fucking write,
there's nothing wrong with that.
What can you do, eh?
I can tell the time.
You can tell the time.
Here, he can tell the time.
Ain't that clever.
It's a lot more than
you can fucking do.
What did you just say to me?
What time is it, Mr Shelby?
That's what I can do.
You little bastard.
Here, keep it.
Stop you from being
late in the future.
Is there forgiveness in your
heart for Arthur Shelby?
No.
But maybe there will be
forgiveness from God.
And you will do God's work?
God is interested in
you as well, Tommy.
And God will be with you on your
journey every step of the way.
He may not need to
take many steps.
Tell me this, Linda
is God interested in me,
or in my money?
I believe you run a foundation
and that your foundation has
many missions across the world
but in these times
of financial crisis,
funding is hard to come by.
So perhaps your God's
plan is a practical one.
Perhaps he would like
me to make a donation
to your foundation
and in return, he would like you
to help my brother on
his road to redemption.
Now, I know that in a place
of worship such as this,
you would never ask how much.
So I will tell you plainly.
I will write your foundation
a cheque for £10,000...
Praise the Lord.
If you agree to look kindly
on Arthur and to help him.
I need to look after
everyone in the family.
Do we have a deal?
Your money will be spent to
do good around the world.
And a mission will
be named after you.
But I am only
agreeing to help him
not sleep with him.
No.
Now, I imagine the negotiation
for that particular favour
would take a considerable
amount of time,
and I have an appointment.
God bless.
LIVERPOOL
DOCKS
Apologies for the
initial misunderstanding.
My brother dealt with it.
For the care you took.
Even though I succumbed
to temptation.
Part of the reason my brother
is back dealing with it,
is down to you,
you spoke to him.
As a comrade.
The beating is
still owed to you.
Do you still do
that kind of work
yourself, Thomas Shelby, MP?
Mr Stagg, see, I can
use men like you.
I have friends that
are in need of guns.
Soon, there will be a shipment
of Thompson sub machine guns
coming here from Boston.
And I need you to unload
and store those weapons.
There will also be ammunition
like this.
You have a good look.
And I need you to take better
care of the guns and ammunition
than you did of the powder.
You understand?
Previously,
all of my import and export
went through Belfast docks.
Now we're dealing with Boston.
I am considering shifting
my supply line to Liverpool.
You'll be a very rich man.
Don't you ever say thank you?
Thank you.
Is that why you
do it, Mr Shelby?
keep all this going?
To have people say thank you?
You could close all this down.
You could leave
the sport behind.
You could live like an
ordinary mortal man.
On your gravestone
"an ordinary mortal man".
But, instead,
you still go round collecting
"please" and "thank you"
and "sorry" and
"forgive me, Mr Shelby."
Is that what it's all for?
You want to know?
You want to know
why I've carried on
all these years?
It's so I can do this.
And then
do this.
Feel it?
I feel it.
Junk doesn't even come close.
Soon, Mr Stagg
when my last piece
of business is done.
I will indeed
be an ordinary mortal man.
You have a good day.
Arthur, we've got a
problem with a referee.
He's not taking the money.
He's fucking religious
or something.
Jesus Christ.
With Tommy away, you're in
charge of gambling, Arthur,
what shall we do?
"And this they said to him,"
"that they may have some
charge to bring against him."
Arthur,
this referee, he's threatening
to go to the police.
"Jesus"
"bent down,"
"and with one finger, he
wrote on the ground..."
Arthur, brother
people are laughing at you.
So I just phoned our
Holy referee - again.
He basically told
me to fuck off.
Not even basically, actually,
he literally told
to me to fuck off.
Is that right? So, do you know?
Oh, for fuck's sake.
Do you know what he
wrote on the ground? Hmm?
No. Do you know? No.
You don't know, do yer?
No, I don't. Billy, do you know
what he wrote on the ground?
I... Hmm?
Do you know what Jesus
wrote on the ground?
He bent down,
and with one finger, he
wrote on the fucking ground.
You know? Do you
know what he wrote?
Come on, Billy. No.
Arthur, what should we do?
Go and get me the referee.
Bring me the fucking referee.
I know she's here with us.
Always.
But still, it's just you and me.
I thought it would be good if
we were in a different place.
I hate that house now.
I wish I could blow it up.
There was a time when we'd
say nothing afterwards
because we didn't
have to say anything.
But now we've got
nothing left to say.
There's business.
What business?
The American.
He's coming to Birmingham.
He's stopping over on
his way to Liverpool.
He is staying with
us tomorrow night.
Frances knows.
She's making up a menu.
And then
we have to make a move.
Do you want to know what
that move is, Lizzie?
No.
I know enough.
Your book of regrets.
23, 24,
52, 55.
The combination to the safe.
Regrets.
And I'm on there.
I'm on the list.
On the very top of the list.
Yep.
Yes, you are.
I regret marrying you, Lizzie.
Cos I've put you
through so much.
I've put you through
all of this. Ruby.
Everything that is to come.
When you married me,
you married a man and
you married a curse.
You have shared my fate.
That is my regret.
But know this, Lizzie.
In this moment,
in this room.
I love you.
You sound like you're
ticking a fucking box,
and I don't know
what's inside the box.
Never have you let me in.
Even though I know the
combination to the safe.
Oh, this is him, is it?
The one who likes to be
fucking difficult, eh?
When I leave this place, I am
going straight to the police.
You are? This man
pointed a gun at me.
Who, him there? Yeah.
Well, let's phone
the police, eh?
Don't worry. We'll have
this sorted out for you.
Hello? Yes, get me the police.
Reports of a man with a
revolver on Watery Lane.
There you go.
And you ask for Inspector Moss.
Chief Superintendent Moss.
He's in charge of Watery
Lane and Bordesley Green.
That's right.
And you see this?
That's his betting
credit with us.
He makes a lot of money
from football matches.
Because we give him the
results before the match.
On Saturday afternoon,
you take this
whistle, and you blow.
You give a penalty
to Birmingham City
in the final minute.
The goalkeeper will let
the penalty go by him,
and Birmingham
City will win 1-0.
All you got to do is...
No.
I won't do it.
If the police won't listen,
I'll go to the newspapers.
I'm not afraid.
I was in France.
Phone Tommy, Arthur.
You shut up.
I am not phoning fucking Tommy.
I am dealing with this, OK?
I'm leaving. You are
going fucking nowhere.
It's time one of us
stood up to you people.
It's not right what's
been happening.
I will not take money to cheat.
Fucking hell.
In France, I ran at the wire.
And I was not afraid.
I am not afraid.
I won't do a bad thing.
I have seen too many bad things.
A beating will
make no difference.
I know that,
cos I can see it in
your fucking eyes.
Fuck.
In the bleak midwinter...
Holy Mary, mother of God.
Ah!
Right, Billy Boy.
You've been in the
family long enough.
Yeah. It's time for
you to get bloodied.
Arthur, you can't. Arthur, please.
You've been with us long enough.
Arthur, fuck, Jesus Christ.
I can't be that
man. Arthur, please.
Either two men die today, Billy,
or one. You fucking decide.
You hate him,
Billy. You hate him.
You don't know him Billy.
He's fucking laughing at you.
Come on, hate him.
Look him in the eyes, man.
Look him in the eyes.
I can't. I can't.
I'm sorry... sorry.
Aaaaah!
Enough. Enough, enough, enough.
All right. Billy B, come on.
Come on, sh...
Sh, sh...
It's all right. It's all right.
Look at you. Look...
Look at you, look.
Huh?
You're bloodied now, Billy.
You're bloodied now.
You're not going
to heaven no more.
They won't let you in.
Isiah, you take
him to the foundry.
And you ask for Mr
Patches, all right?
You tell him we got some
fuel for the furnace.
Who the fuck are you?
Ah! Ah!
I hear... Please.
You're the informant inside
the Shelby organisation.
And who the fuck I am
is the man who you now work for.
Please, please...
I have some things I need you to do,
and I want to impress upon you...
To IMPRESS... Ah! Ah!
Upon you the seriousness
of my intent.
Cos, you see, I used to do this
kind of thing for a living.
And sometimes I kind of miss it.
Just like Mr Shelby,
I miss the... the wave
of electricity you
get under your scalp.
I miss the taste like metal
on the tip of your tongue.
I am about to give
you an instruction.
You do as I say,
you stay a man.
Fail,
and I will send people to
serve your balls to you
on a china plate.
I'll do what you say.
A decision has been taken.
My associates are going to
take care of Tommy Shelby.
And you are going to give
us up his brother, Arthur.
Do you understand?
Yes... Yes. Fucking yes. Please.
Only information leading to
the murder of Arthur Shelby
will save you from
an Italian death.
Cos it was the Italians
that taught me that
above God, above children,
above his wife and
above his mother
most of all, a man
loves his balls.
Oh...
Hello, Arthur.
I think we should pray.
That's how we begin this.
You'd like to pray?
The prayer I have chosen is the
Act of Contrition, version two.
So, you're Catholic now, Linda?
You're Catholic.
Quakers don't pray.
Bow your head, Arthur,
and close your eyes.
And recite the prayer.
You know it well from
when you were boy.
Oh, my mind's all dried
up with junk, though,
and shot full of fuck...
Shot full of holes.
Linda, please.
It's in there somewhere,
Arthur. It's like a song.
Yeah.
Somewhere.
Together, we'll find it.
Digging for the words
will help clean your soul.
I'll begin it.
Forgive me my sins, oh,
Lord, forgive me my sins.
The sins of my youth.
The sins of my youth,
the sins of my age,
the sins of my soul.
The sins of my body.
The sins I know,
the sins I know not.
The sins I have
concealed for so long.
For so fu...
For so long.
I caught him stealing a car.
And he's got a stack of
cash from the betting shop.
Steal from who you want,
but don't steal from me.
Here you are.
Get a train to wherever the
fuck you want to go. Get out.
I don't ride trains.
Is that a fact?
Well, Curly has a
two-wheeled wagon.
What am I, a tinker?
I need four wheels.
And a horse for the hills.
Which hills?
All of them. All the
hills of England.
Why do you want to leave?
I didn't take to that
work in the betting shop.
Well, you heard him, Charlie.
Get my dad's old four-wheeled
wagon and two strong ponies.
Right.
Curly! Get here.
Before you go,
do you want to know the
truth about yourself?
No. Who does?
Well, I am going to tell yer.
That spring at Appleby Fair,
your mother stole
my watch and chain.
You're from a long
line of thieves.
The watch had the words
"Saxon Shore" carved in it.
I stole it myself from a
drunk when I was a kid.
I imagine she told you
your dad was the Duke
of the Saxon Shore.
Well
I am the Duke,
it was my watch.
I am your father.
That's the truth.
When her dad found out,
he shot me in the chest
with a squirrel gun.
A scar and a stolen watch
and a story she made up.
That's all you need
to know about yourself
before you get on the road.
Esme told me the
spirits favour you.
That the spirit is in you.
She tried to sell me like one
of those horses, didn't she?
How much did she pay for me?
I have no use for gold any more.
But if you're a horse,
you're in the right place.
Curly!
Curly. Hurry up.
This boy has hills to climb.
I remember that watch.
Oh, yeah?
She used to wear
it over her heart.
We buried it with her.
Tom. The old wagon's right
front wheel is fucked, Tom.
It's standing in the wet.
Put a new one on, Curly.
Yeah.
They fix wagons here.
Good families come
from the New Forest
to have their wagons fixed
and get fresh horses
before the fairs.
Yeah. Yeah, I like it here.
I like it better than
that betting shop.
Why?
People.
People piss me off.
There are a lot of people
in that betting shop.
So far, here I've
only counted two.
Uh-huh.
Charlie and Curly,
the rest is dogs and horses.
Curly's half horse himself.
Dogs are OK.
Horses are better
than people, mind you.
There's work here for
a man who knows horses.
Unknown.
I want to remain
completely unknown.
Well, you'd be in the right
place for that as well.
No-one knows anyone here.
Hey, mister. Save
that wheel a minute.
Where would I stay?
Stables, with the
other stallions.
Now that Finn is married off,
there are plenty of
girls round here.
Their fathers are
mostly unarmed.
I have a future for you, Duke.
You already have a son.
My business has two sides.
Light and dark.
I'll need someone for each.
And I'm dark, am I?
I have realised we don't get
to choose which one we are.
Dark knows dark.
And my affairs,
both light and dark
will need settling soon.
Curly? Find a shovel for the
Duke of the Saxon Shore here.
Get him shovelling shit.
And put some petrol in the boat.
I'm off to meet a
lady in Solihull.
♪ One silver dollar
♪ Bright silver dollar
♪ Changing hands, changing hands
♪ Spent for a beer he's drinking
♪ Worn by a gambler's lust
♪ Pierced by an outlaw's bullet
♪ And lost in the blood-red dust
♪ One silver dollar
♪ One silver dollar... ♪
Take a look at her.
Now imagine ten
people living on side.
Step on. Have a look inside.
I've had a response
from the Guinness Trust
about building charitable
housing at two sites
along the canal
network between London,
Birmingham and Liverpool.
This lock here would be
the one of the sites.
I have the permission.
We just need the finance.
I know that you and your husband,
Bryan Guinness, are estranged,
but I understand you
still have influence
in the Guinness family.
Your support might help
them make their decision.
Will you help me?
I've booked a suite in a
hotel a mile from here.
My chauffeur will take us there.
You look quite the
thing dressed like that,
dressed like a working man.
They'll probably show
you to the coal house
to make your delivery.
Yep, they probably will.
Oswald has fucked your wife,
so my suggestion is about
balance and proportion.
It would be only fair.
Can I assume.
I have your support?
This isn't about charitable housing,
this is about changing the world.
It's about a different
kind of trust.
Absolute trust.
We have important
work ahead of us.
It's much harder to lie
with your body than
with your words.
This, I have learnt.
Mostly, I do whatever
I want to do.
Sometimes, I do
things for the cause.
In this case, it's both.
Come.
In the interests of
absolute clarity,
that is simply
the English aristocracy's
way of shaking hands.
So...
Welcome.
♪ Come under my
wings, little bird
♪ Come under my wings... ♪
♪ Unmade
♪ I swear that there's nothing
♪ Up my sleeves
♪ And then back again
♪ I swear there's nothing
♪ Unmade
♪ There's no faces
♪ Won't grow back again
♪ Broken pieces... ♪
If you do this thing
the possibility of war,
you have to consider.
It was the ambitions
and strategies of one
man that caused this.
There will be
a war in this family.
And one of you will die.
♪ I swear there's nothing
♪ Won't grow back again
♪ I swear there's nothing... ♪
We need to leave early to catch
the first train to Liverpool, yes?
Yep.
So eat early, finish early.
You changed the
combination of the safe.
Why?
Have you got new secrets?
With the new business at hand,
there are some things
that I cannot share.
What things?
What are those tablets?
The doctor gave them me.
Pain killers?
Yeah. What pain?
Any pain that comes, Lizzie.
When you're ready, I want
you to tell me everything
that's going on.
It's like the clock's
stopped ticking
and I'm waiting for
the bomb to explode.
We are in that quiet minute.
Tommy?
That's where we live now.
When I know everything.
I will tell you everything.
Oh, no, Gina's
running wild, y'see.
Harrods, dope, amphetamines,
lords and ladies,
you know, the whole
English aristocracy thing.
Fuck wine - whiskey.
Shelby, you having whiskey?
I'll stay on wine.
Fuck wine, more whiskey.
I'm celebrating.
Celebration, you know. Getting
off this fucking island.
You see, the thing with England,
the currency here,
it's not money.
Nah. You got bored of
money a long time ago.
Cos you know anyone
can have money,
you can fucking
you can fucking find
money in the mud.
You can forge money.
Mr Shelby, you can
steal money, am I right?
The currency here, it's blood.
And Mr Shelby knows that
better than all of them.
Blood here is like wine,
like the vintage wine in
that bottle. It's the label,
it's the terroir, it's the
grape that makes the wine.
Who fucking cares about
the glass around it?
And you, my friend,
you're an American.
You fucking smash the glass,
you spill the blood
and you spend their currency
to get what you want.
Am I right?
When you come to America,
I will show you things.
You're going to America?
To Canada, Lizzie, to collect
payment for the shipment.
I need to do it myself.
And who will be going with you?
Michael will be there
to watch his back.
Another journey, Tommy?
$5 million, Mrs Shelby.
It's worth a little
cruise, don't you think?
You know whiskey
does talk, Mr Nelson,
and sometimes whiskey
is... very eloquent.
But $5 million, Mr Nelson...
Now, that is a legacy.
And when I come back,
I will know everything.
I see myself so clearly
in you, Thomas Shelby.
You are a man with a bright
and glittering future.
Mr Shelby, there's a
car coming up the drive.
A Rolls-Royce.
Were you expecting more guests?
No.
Excuse me.
We were on our way to my
constituency in Smethwick
and I heard our American
friend was in Birmingham
and that he was coming here,
so we came to say
one last farewell.
Champagne. We have
much to celebrate.
It isn't that I wasn't sure
Mr Shelby would give you
an excellent
send-off, I just felt,
since telegrams and wires
and letters can so
easily be intercepted,
we might confirm all that we've
achieved during your visit
over champagne.
It is remarkable how quickly our
relationships have developed.
So many triangles in this room.
Everyone except from Mr Nelson
is the point of a triangle.
How am I part of a triangle?
Mr Nelson, you have
all that you came for?
I have confirmation that
the future of Europe is in
the hands of men
like yourselves.
And that urgent conversations
between Washington,
Rome and of course
Berlin can now begin.
A two-week visit that may have
changed the course of history.
We have all got what we wanted.
Yes.
And I got what I have wanted
from the moment I set eyes on it.
Elizabeth, you are
a very lucky woman
to have each day what I
have only sampled once.
Forgive us, Mr Nelson,
that was a necessary
bit of housekeeping.
Thomas.
We do so hate to be indiscreet,
but we have told you many times,
if you are to seek power in
these days of shiny magazines
and society photographs,
sooner or later, you will
have to find a spouse
who is more suitable.
A woman with Lizzie's past
and personal history
really isn't suitable.
She doesn't deserve
you, Mr Shelby.
You know the thing is, Mosley
you're right.
You're right, she
doesn't deserve me.
She doesn't deserve what I am.
She doesn't deserve
what I will become.
What will you become?
The truth is, I belong
here, at this table.
With fuckers like you.
She doesn't.
For all I try to hide it...
..I'm just one of you.
Could there be a
sadder ending, eh?
♪ Take a little walk
to the edge of town
♪ And go across the tracks
♪ Where a viaduct looms
like a bird of doom
♪ As it shifts and cracks
♪ Where secrets lie
in the border fires
♪ In the humming wires
♪ Hey, man
♪ You know you're
never coming back
♪ Past the square
♪ Past the bridge, past
the mills and the stacks
♪ On a gathering storm
♪ Comes a tall, handsome man
♪ And a dusty black coat
with a red right hand. ♪
I'm here on behalf of your
wife, Gina, and Jack Nelson.
Mr Nelson's prepared
to get you out of here.
But first he needs an
answer to the question.
If the answer is yes
you'll be released.
If the answer is no
you'll stay.
I have consulted my mother.
Your mother's dead.
Never the less, I
have consulted her.
And yes.
When I'm released,
it is my intention
to kill Tommy Shelby.
♪ He's a god, he's a man
♪ He's a ghost, a guru
♪ And they're
whispering his name
♪ Through the disappearing land
♪ But hidden in his coat
♪ Is a red right hand
♪ You don't have no money?
♪ Well, he get you some
♪ You don't have no car?
♪ He get you one. ♪